<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">



<title>Jessica R. Barnett, Ph.D.</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
<icon>/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
<subtitle>Personal website of Buffalo-based pianist slash music theorist slash educator Jessica Barnett.</subtitle>
<link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
<link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
<updated>2015-06-29T12:18:52-04:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Jessica Barnett</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>barnett.jessica@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title>Tuition and Policies</title>
  <link href="/studio/tuition-and-policies/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>/studio/tuition-and-policies</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Barnett</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
    <email>barnett.jessica@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/background.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tuition and Policies feature&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;sidebar-left top&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h6 class=&quot;toc-title&quot;&gt;Studio Information&lt;/h6&gt;
	&lt;ul class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio&quot;&gt;About My Studio&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/tuition-and-policies&quot;&gt;Tuition and Policies&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;!--&lt;ul&gt;	
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&quot;#Tuition&quot;&gt;Costs&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#attendance&#39;&gt;Attendance and Cancellation&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#practicing&#39;&gt;Practicing&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&quot;#performance&quot;&gt;Performance Opportunities&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#supplies&#39;&gt;Supplies&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;--&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;	
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About Me&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Me&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monthly tuition is due at the first lesson of each month and can be paid via check, cash, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://venmo.com&quot;&gt;electronically&lt;/a&gt;. I will issue a monthly invoice and receipt electronically. Families with two or more students will receive a $5 discount per student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuition encompasses lesson time and overhead costs, which include materials, recitals, and piano maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson lengths are recommended below and vary by student age, level, and budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
	&lt;thead&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;Length&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;In My Studio&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;At Your Home&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/thead&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				&lt;em&gt;30 minutes&lt;/em&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				$30
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				$35
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				Best for young children and beginners who have never played the instrument before.
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				&lt;em&gt;45 minutes&lt;/em&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				$40
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				$45
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				Great for adult beginners, high schoolers, and advanced children who are very serious about learning the instrument.
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				&lt;em&gt;60 minutes&lt;/em&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				$50
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				$55
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				For advanced students and pianists preparing for competitions or recitals. 
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	&lt;a name=&quot;attendance&quot;&gt;Attendance and Cancellation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular attendance is expected and necessary to make progress. If a lesson must be cancelled, please contact me 24 hours in advance via phone, text, or email. If I cancel an already scheduled lesson, I will make it up as soon as possible and at your convenience, or you will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	&lt;a name=&quot;practicing&quot;&gt;
		Practicing
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming a great pianist requires regular, quality practice at home. Lessons focus on the development of effective practice skills that build not only strength, coordination and musicality, but also focus, self-discipline, and the ability to solve problems — skills that help us all be more productive humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is essential that young students, especially beginners, receive active and positive parental involvement outside of the lesson time. Parents are encouraged to ask questions or share observations about their child’s progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	Performance Opportunities
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;performance&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Recitals: All students ages 18 and under should plan to perform in a minimum of two studio recitals each year. Adult students have the option to participate. All recitals are open to the public; family and friends are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Competitive Events: Please let the teacher know if the student is interested in participating in piano and/or composition competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	&lt;a name=&quot;supplies&quot;&gt;
		Supplies
	&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A well-maintained grand or upright piano, or a professional keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repertoire assigned by the teacher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A notebook or three-ring binder to record practice goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pro-metronome-tempo-keeping/id477960671?mt=8&quot;&gt;metronome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/tuition-and-policies/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tuition and Policies&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica Barnett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica R. Barnett, Ph.D.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title>Piano Studio</title>
  <link href="/studio/contact/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>/studio/contact</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Barnett</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
    <email>barnett.jessica@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/background.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Piano Studio feature&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;sidebar-left top&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h6 class=&quot;toc-title&quot;&gt;Studio Information&lt;/h6&gt;
	&lt;ul class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio&quot;&gt;About My Studio&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/tuition-and-policies&quot;&gt;Tuition and Policies&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;!--&lt;ul&gt;	
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&quot;#Tuition&quot;&gt;Costs&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#attendance&#39;&gt;Attendance and Cancellation&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#practicing&#39;&gt;Practicing&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&quot;#performance&quot;&gt;Performance Opportunities&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#supplies&#39;&gt;Supplies&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;--&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;	
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About Me&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Me&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;contact-me&quot;&gt;Contact Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have more questions? Sent me a note at barnett.jessica at gmail dot com, or fill out the form below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form id=&quot;form1&quot; name=&quot;form1&quot; class=&quot;wufoo  page&quot; accept-charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot; autocomplete=&quot;off&quot; enctype=&quot;multipart/form-data&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; novalidate=&quot;&quot; action=&quot;https://jessicarbarnett.wufoo.com/forms/zhomijw0fmc5r0/&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;foli7&quot; class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;
      &lt;label class=&quot;desc&quot; id=&quot;title7&quot; for=&quot;Field7&quot;&gt; Name &lt;/label&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;input id=&quot;Field7&quot; name=&quot;Field7&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; class=&quot;field text large&quot; value=&quot;&quot; maxlength=&quot;255&quot; tabindex=&quot;1&quot; onkeyup=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;foli2&quot; class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;
      &lt;label class=&quot;desc&quot; id=&quot;title2&quot; for=&quot;Field2&quot;&gt; Email address &lt;span id=&quot;req_2&quot; class=&quot;req&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/label&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;input id=&quot;Field2&quot; name=&quot;Field2&quot; type=&quot;email&quot; spellcheck=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;field text large&quot; value=&quot;&quot; maxlength=&quot;255&quot; tabindex=&quot;2&quot; required=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;instruct&quot; id=&quot;instruct2&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Your email address will remain private and won&#39;t be shared with anyone.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;foli1&quot; class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;
      &lt;label class=&quot;desc&quot; id=&quot;title1&quot; for=&quot;Field1&quot;&gt; Message &lt;span id=&quot;req_1&quot; class=&quot;req&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/label&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;textarea id=&quot;Field1&quot; name=&quot;Field1&quot; class=&quot;field textarea medium&quot; spellcheck=&quot;true&quot; rows=&quot;10&quot; cols=&quot;50&quot; tabindex=&quot;3&quot; onkeyup=&quot;&quot; required=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;buttons&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;input id=&quot;saveForm&quot; name=&quot;saveForm&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Send Message&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;hidden&quot;&gt;
      &lt;label for=&quot;comment&quot;&gt;Do Not Fill This Out&lt;/label&gt;
      &lt;textarea name=&quot;comment&quot; id=&quot;comment&quot; rows=&quot;1&quot; cols=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
      &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; id=&quot;idstamp&quot; name=&quot;idstamp&quot; value=&quot;DXSyHZyBYpNZI+88LvVOKO8dSfd/5lyIeCQAXFVxeJY=&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/contact/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Piano Studio&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica Barnett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica R. Barnett, Ph.D.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title>Gangnam Style, Arts Education, and the US Economy</title>
  <link href="/blog/gagnam-style-arts-education-us-economy/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/gagnam-style-arts-education-us-economy</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Barnett</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
    <email>barnett.jessica@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/gagnam-feature.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gangnam Style, Arts Education, and the US Economy feature&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/&quot;&gt;NPR’s Planet Money&lt;/a&gt; podcast is one of my favorite things to listen to when I’m running. In a recent episode, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2012/10/16/163039109/episode-410-why-k-pop-is-taking-over-the-world&quot;&gt;“Why K-Pop is Taking over the World,”&lt;/a&gt; they discuss how South Korea has positioned itself to be a major player in pop music all across the world. It’s kind of strange to think of pop music as a commodity, but it really is, and one we’ve exported to the rest of the world for a long time. It took us more than 100 years to establish a pop music industry in America, and by making smart investments, learning from us ( and getting a bit lucky) Korea’s managed to kickstart a pop music industry in just 20 years by—as the Planet Money folks put it—figuring how to “manufacture, distribute, and ‘package’ ” music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the episode is devoted to showing how they’ve done this, how all of that work has laid a foundation for songs like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9bZkp7q19f0&quot;&gt;Gangam Style&lt;/a&gt;. The song’s symbolic of the fact that Korea has become a real player in the world’s larger cultural industry. For the Koreans, investing in the industry was in many ways a brilliant economic strategy. Planet Money makes the case that when people in other countries listen to our music, watch our movies, and so on, they become much more likely to buy our stuff, visit our country, and associate things made in the US with quality. A strong cultural industry is an incredible form of soft power: it gives us the ability to influence the values of a large population of the world without fighting wars or giving them money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it seems to me that it’s in America’s best interests to maintain our edge as net exporters of cultural products. After listening to the episode, I kept thinking how valuable long-dead artists and musicians are to cities all across Europe. It’s always valuable to debate whether investments we make will return value to US taxpayers, but this episode in particular made me think how difficult it must be to calculate the real value of investing just a dollar into something like arts education.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/gagnam-style-arts-education-us-economy/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Gangnam Style, Arts Education, and the US Economy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica Barnett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica R. Barnett, Ph.D.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title>Using Spotify in the Aural Skills Classroom</title>
  <link href="/blog/using-spotify-in-the-aural-skills-classroom/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/using-spotify-in-the-aural-skills-classroom</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Barnett</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
    <email>barnett.jessica@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/dictation-feature.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Using Spotify in the Aural Skills Classroom feature&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At Furman we are really lucky to have well-equipped classrooms that make it very easy to display a computer screen, project a score, and play music from a device with audio output. Partly as a result of this, and after reading a bunch of excellent blog posts by &lt;a href=&quot;http://kris.shaffermusic.com/&quot;&gt;Kris Shaffer&lt;/a&gt; about incorporating technology into music theory classes, I’ve found myself making greater use of online resources in my classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, I used many of the great ideas in &lt;a href=&quot;http://jmtp.ou.edu/author/brian-alegant&quot;&gt;Brian Alegant’s “Listen Up!: Thoughts on iPods, Sonata Form, and Analysis without Score,” (Journal of Music Theory Pedagogy 21)&lt;/a&gt; when I taught form to sophomores. Alegant’s basic point—and this has become even more true since the article was published—is that great recordings are at our fingertips, and it’s easier than it’s ever been to use them in and out of the classroom. When I taught the Form and Analysis part of that class, I often used the online recording databases that Furman subscribes to. Lots of universities have subscriptions to the Naxos Library or the EMI Classical Music library. (Furman also subscribes to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dramonline.org/&quot;&gt;DRAM&lt;/a&gt;, a particularly nice archive of American music recorded on the New World Records and CRI labels.) These are all great resources, but I realized fairly quickly that they aren’t great for in-class use. Their search functions are not particularly intuitive, and, because they are browser-based, they can be unreliable. Even when I’d create a playlist before class, I could never be sure that a recording was really going to play when I pressed the play button! For all of these reasons, my students are even less likely to use them outside of class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the ability to incorporate good-quality recorded music into my classes has become too important to me to give up because of these shortcomings. Furman’s theory curriculum is structured around Steve Laitz’s “The Complete Musician,” and the most recent edition, which separates workbooks into “written” and “musicianship” skills, has made it even easier to use Laitz as a stand-alone aural skills text. On the musicianship side, Laitz’s text really emphasizes holistic listening skills: bass-line dictation, form identification, and so on. And students develop these skills through listening to a variety of instrumental and vocal ensembles playing “real music.”These are tough skills to master, and unlike harmonic idioms, melodic dictation—more traditional listening skills—I can’t emulate a string quartet in class!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laitz’s musicianship workbook is fairly-well stocked with examples—more than I can get to in class—but students always want more practice, and it’s nice to have lots of extra examples if you want to emphasize something in particular. For example, I’ve been teaching modulation mostly in relation to the opening phrase of Minuets. Laitz has a few examples, but I want my students to have lots of exposure to these types of piece.  They’ll be composing one for an end-of-term project, and in addition to being great pieces for studying modulation, they are great pieces for studying phrase structure and for becoming acquainted within certain Classical schemata. We’ve been talking about “Montes, Fontes, and Pontes,” in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spotify.com&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; is a relatively new, but really wonderful resource for recordings of all kinds of music. And it’s great for in-class use because it is easy to search, and it isn’t browser-based. Most importantly, I can count on music playing when I click play. I’ve been using Spotify along with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://remoteless.no/&quot;&gt;Remoteless app&lt;/a&gt; for iPhone so that I can play music while walking around the class and watching/helping my students. It’s an even better tool outside of class. I’ve been creating Spotify playlists stocked with listening examples that are relevant to whatever we are working on in class. ~~For example, here’s my playlist for modulation and binary form.~~ I send my students that playlist, along with a DropBox link to a folder containing a list of the listening excerpts from the playlist and screenshots of the answers taken from IMSLP. Students pick something to listen to, note the key, and try dictate the bass line, identify what type of phrase they hear, and so on. Most importantly, this is all really easy for me to maintain. If I hear something promising on Spotify, I can easily drag it to the appropriate playlist, drop a screenshot of the passage from IMSLP into the DropBox, and type its title, key, and the location of the passage (for example, 0:00-0:17) into the DropBox text file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hopes are that all of this makes my students more likely to spend time listening outside of class. Listening skills are difficult to improve for lots of reasons. Because class time is limited, I want to remove any practical barriers that limit my students’s ability to practice on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/using-spotify-in-the-aural-skills-classroom/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Using Spotify in the Aural Skills Classroom&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica Barnett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica R. Barnett, Ph.D.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title>Dropvox</title>
  <link href="/blog/dropvox/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/dropvox</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Barnett</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
    <email>barnett.jessica@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/dropvox-feature.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dropvox feature&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now that I’m thinking about it, another classroom tool I’ve used a lot this year is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0CCIQFjAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.irradiatedsoftware.com%2Fdropvox%2F&amp;amp;ei=oyozVKrxEvCLsQS1uoCICQ&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNENarLqy6aNKM2XjoyJilkAihA7VQ&amp;amp;sig2=A7gCIxnjmK1cvm-NOKLTDA&amp;amp;bvm=bv.76943099,d.cWc&quot;&gt;DropVox&lt;/a&gt;. It’s functionality isn’t a lot different from the Memos app that comes pre-installed on iPhones. But, DropVox automatically uploads anything you record to a folder in your DropBox for you to listen to on a better set of speakers later. It’s a really helpful little app if you grade students on prepared singing, sight-singing, and so on. I’ve been using Lore as a course management site this year (it’s kind of like Moodle, but a bit more social), and it allows me to leave comments with grades that I post. Having DropVox recordings in addition to whatever notes I might make in class really helps me give better feedback to my students. And Lore allows you to upload those files along with your students’s grades so that they can hear themselves, too.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/dropvox/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Dropvox&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica Barnett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica R. Barnett, Ph.D.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title>Resources</title>
  <link href="/studio/resources/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>/studio/resources</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Barnett</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
    <email>barnett.jessica@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/background.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Resources feature&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;sidebar-left top&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h6 class=&quot;toc-title&quot;&gt;Studio Information&lt;/h6&gt;
	&lt;ul class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio&quot;&gt;About My Studio&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/tuition-and-policies&quot;&gt;Tuition and Policies&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;!--&lt;ul&gt;	
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&quot;#Tuition&quot;&gt;Costs&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#attendance&#39;&gt;Attendance and Cancellation&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#practicing&#39;&gt;Practicing&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&quot;#performance&quot;&gt;Performance Opportunities&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;a href=&#39;#supplies&#39;&gt;Supplies&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;--&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;	
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;About Me&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Me&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;repertoire-and-materials&quot;&gt;Repertoire and Materials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheet music is available from a variety of sources online (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pianoatpepper.com/&quot;&gt;Piano at Pepper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jwpepper.com/sheet-music/piano-sheet-music.jsp&quot;&gt;JW Pepper&lt;/a&gt;) and in the Buffalo area (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.illos.com&quot;&gt;Illos Pianos&lt;/a&gt;). On occassion, sheet music is available for free through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://imslp.org&quot;&gt;Interational Music Score Library Project&lt;/a&gt;. I am more than happy to purchase materials directly and send you a bill for the materials at-cost (including shipping, if applicable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to their music, students should bring a notebook to every lesson so  that I can record practice notes, relay messages, and keep track of our progress and goals. Students (and parents) may also use this notebook for journaling practice habits, asking questions, or generally expressing their musical aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students should invest in a metronome to insure quality practicing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pro-metronome-tempo-keeping/id477960671?mt=8&quot;&gt;Metronome apps&lt;/a&gt; are available on your smartphone, and quality, affordable metronomes are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Matrix-MR600-Deluxe-Metronome/dp/B0002F6ZJS/ref=sr_1_12?s=musical-instruments&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1432250811&amp;amp;sr=1-12&quot;&gt;available online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;piano-maintenance&quot;&gt;Piano Maintenance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Buffalo area, we have a number of exceptional piano stores and repair technicians. For piano maintenance, I highly recommend both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.music.buffalo.edu/faculty/staff&quot;&gt;Sharon Mok&lt;/a&gt; at the University at Buffalo and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.illos.com&quot;&gt;Illos Pianos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;music-theory-resources&quot;&gt;Music Theory Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theory tutorials, flash cards, ear-training drills, staff paper, etc. are available at &lt;a href=&quot;www.musictheory.net&quot;&gt;http://musictheory.net&lt;/a&gt;. There are number of wonderful iPhone, iPad, and Android apps as well.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/studio/resources/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica Barnett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jessica R. Barnett, Ph.D.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


</feed>